Amur.
Hey.
Ha ha ha ha.
Oh, I just knew you'd be by the lake again.
Hey.
This month's meat,
vegetables and daily supplies
are all on the counter.
Mm.
Alright, Mongke.
Put it on my tab.
Hey.
Your tab, y'know...
it's been over half a year.
How's business lately?
Why don't you settle up last quarter first?
Business?
Same as always.
Hit or miss.
Hey, if business ain't good, get out there.
Hand out some flyers, y'know.
Oh right.
Where's Xiaohei?
How come he's not back yet?
I can't hear him barking.
Feels kinda strange.
Xiaohei...
don't know where he went.
Went out looking but couldn't find him.
Let's wait a bit more.
Maybe if we wait,
he'll come back on his own.
Without Xiaohei to help out,
it's really been a lot of trouble, y'know.
Before, whenever you ordered stuff,
Xiaohei would carry it over himself.
Hey.
You don't think Xiaohei got eaten
by wolves on the way?
Oh, go on, get outta here.
You're the one who'd get eaten by wolves.
Hey, it's getting dark, head home.
Any later and there really might be wolves.
I ain't scared of no wolves.
You study hard now.
Do well on your exam.
You're so long-winded.
I'm already studying, aren't I?
Yeah yeah, alright alright.
I'm off, I'm off.
Let's go, Xiaohei.
Woof woof.
Xiaohei's hungry?
Woof woof woof woof woof woof woof woof.
Xiaohei's really hungry?
Woof woof woof woof woof.
Then let's get you something tasty?
Woof woof woof.
Come on!
I'm from Singapore.
Before my father passed, he said
"A person should see the great grasslands"
That way, when you go,
you won't have any regrets.
I came to the grasslands
with my own willfulness.
I never expected
to encounter a pack of wolves.
Fortunately,
a black dog saved me
and brought me here.
Hey.
Where I met him.
Who are you?
Hey.
What happened to you?
You're...
Ah.
You're awake.
Here, let me take a look.
(Symptoms in the Pharmacy: A Guide to
the Management of Common Illnesses)
I'm a doctor.
Stay still, don't move.
The low fever has passed.
Hungry?
Here, let me get you a bowl of meat.
Um...
Where are my clothes?
You were soaking wet when you arrived.
I washed them and hung them out to dry.
So I'm naked?
Oh.
Wait just a moment.
Here, they're dry now.
Oh, good.
Let me pour you some milk tea.
Um, sorry.
Could you...
could you step out for a moment?
Oh.
Sure.
Eat up. Weren't you just hungry?
Let me tell you
I stewed this meat for a long time.
I put in sea buckthorn, cistanche,
and more. Here.
Hey, eat up.
Oh right, and this piece too.
Here.
Bring your bowl over, quick.
Dip it in this, it's good.
Here.
How come you're not asking where I'm from?
No need to ask.
When you want to tell me, you will.
Are you preparing for med school?
It's a medical license exam.
Thank you for saving my life.
You'll definitely become
a really good doctor.
Saving you?
That's an exaggeration.
At most, I just helped out.
That was still a big help.
Otherwise I really might have died.
On the grasslands,
We're all children of the Eternal Sky.
We should help each other.
You're right.
Hello, my name is Lei Zexin,
from Singapore.
That far away!
Yes.
Here for sightseeing?
Backpacking trip.
Lei Zexin.
Your Mandarin is quite good.
Yes, my father was from mainland China.
Then how'd you end up
in such a mess on a trip?
And hurt too.
I got lost.
Looking at your wound,
something bit you, didn't it?
I'm embarrassed to say
I encountered wolves on the way.
Well, you're lucky to be alive.
Please don't make fun of me.
Do you live here all by yourself?
Yes.
Just me.
Running this guesthouse.
What does this symbol mean?
Amur.
That's my name.
You're the first patient I've treated.
I'm leaving a signature as a memento.
You don't mind, do you?
Not at all.
I think it's cute.
Tomorrow I'll have Mongke
take you to the station.
It's hard to catch a ride around here.
Station?
Yes.
To go where?
Aren't you here for sightseeing?
Nowhere you want to go?
I don't know where to go.
That's perfect then.
Why don't you stay here?
Stay here?
Yeah.
I'm the owner of this guesthouse.
You can stay as long as you want.
If you stay long enough,
I can even give you a discount.
This is all the cash I have.
It's all yours.
Wow.
Welcome to Amur's Guesthouse!
The grasslands are your home.
Stay as long as you like!
I'll hold onto this
and refund any extra later.
What's this dog's name?
He...
His name is Xiaohei.
The best sheepdog on this grassland.
Xiaohei,
where did he go?
He...
probably off playing somewhere.
Maybe he'll come back in a few days.
Finally, a guest!
Hey.
I'll prepare your room right now.
The best room.
I guarantee you'll feel right at home.
Okay.
You're awake.
Come on!
Slow down, there's more.
Amur.
Mm.
This room of yours...
is the best.
The best room, of course,
goes to the best guest.
Where would you like to go
these next few days?
I can be your guide.
Nowhere I want to go anymore.
It's nice right here.
Not going to look around?
I'm worried you'll get bored
if you stay too long.
Staying here
might just be the place
I've traveled so far to find.
Alright.
Stay as long as you like.
Who told you to pay so much anyway.
There you go again.
Hey.
Here?
This is the spot.
Oh right, Amur.
If you pass the medical license exam,
where do you plan to work?
A pet clinic.
A pet clinic?
Yes, I'm taking
the veterinary license exam.
What?
And you went treating me like that?
Hey, you got better, didn't you?
Let me tell you
humans and animals are the same in the end.
The medical theory is identical.
I really can't with you.
Actually, I should thank you instead.
For letting me get some good practice.
Hey, how about you become
a partner in my pet clinic?
Partner?
Yes.
Are you asking me to invest in you?
Hey, don't worry.
If I'm going to rip off customers,
I won't target just one.
You say that so righteously.
Then how about you invest your skills
in the pet clinic?
Speaking of which,
what about this guesthouse?
Will you still run it?
And also
your pet clinic...
where would it be? In the city?
The pet clinic...
Actually, it'd be more
of an animal hospital.
Right here.
To treat all the injured animals.
Like when someone's horse gets hurt
or someone's sheep rolls down a hillside
and people's dogs...
Auntie Wang's, Auntie Li's, and so on.
I'll heal them all.
Amur.
That's a great plan.
I'm in.
It might leave a scar.
If you mind,
I could get a cosmetology license too.
Oh, please don't.
Don't use me as your test subject, okay?
I'm just teasing.
Actually, a scar isn't so bad.
It'll be a memento.
A memento of escaping from wolves?
A memento
of you saving me.
Sweet talker.
Really.
If I hadn't been hurt,
I wouldn't have met you.
And I wouldn't have gotten to enjoy
breakfast bathed in morning light.
Then
am I more important
or the morning light
or the breakfast?
You're the most important, of course.
But the morning light matters too
and so does breakfast.
More importantly,
you
are my breakfast.
Hey.
Let me clean up.
Thank you.
What are you looking at?
The clouds.
The clouds are flowing.
It's like they're swirling around us.
Standing here.
It's as if I'm standing
at the center of the world.
Amur.
Have you
ever felt that way?
Sorry.
Mr. Lei Zexin.
Your feeling
might be wrong.
Wrong?
THAT is where the center of the world is.
The center of the world
is over there.
Yes.
Can you feel it?
Feel what?
Try feeling it again.
Whoa, I can feel it.
I feel it.
You're very alluring.
Hey.
Be serious.
I am being serious.
Very seriously
admiring you.
Oh come on.
That's not what I meant.
Then what did you mean?
Listen,
when I was very young,
a meteorite once fell here.
We're lying on top
of that meteorite right now.
Are you serious?
Of course I'm serious.
Pretty cool, right?
Think about it.
A meteorite drifting
through the infinite cosmos.
One day, with a one-in-a-billion chance,
it lands on Earth.
Boom.
Right here.
A direct hit.
Doesn't that make this
the center of the world?
A direct hit.
It sounds like you're saying
the meteorite chose where to land.
Why couldn't it have?
All coincidences in this world
are actually choices.
Think about it, the grasslands are so vast.
Even if you got lost,
why did you end up here, of all places?
Wasn't that your own choice?
Would you say this is the center
of the world?
Mm...
Yeah?
See? Then how about I sell this to you?
Just a thousand yuan
and the center of the world is all yours.
Oh come on, think about it.
If you're interested,
I'll give you a discount.
Totally worth it.
Hey hey hey hey, don't go.
Hey.
Well then
sell yourself to me too.
That might be very expensive.
Name your price.
Oh no no no.
How expensive exactly?
Name your price.
Priceless.
Priceless?
So it's free then.
No no, no.
Priceless means it's very expensive.
Expensive.
Expensive?
Yes.
No matter how expensive,
I'll owe you the difference
and pay it off slowly.
Didn't you say
this is the center of the world?
What do you want to do
at the center of the world?
At the center of this world, I want to
hold you.
Love you.
Be by your side.
Until...
the last day of my life.
Really?
Amur.
Mongke.
Ha ha ha ha.
Oh, my friend!
Come.
Huh?
Is this a new guest?
Yes, his name is Lei Zexin.
This is Mongke.
He delivers supplies regularly.
Oh.
Right.
Mongke, hello, thanks for your hard work.
Oh hey, hello hello hello hello.
Amur here's my best friend.
If you're his guest,
Then you're definitely my guest too.
How d'ya like the grasslands?
Good good good, thanks.
Come come come, sit sit sit.
And the food? Food good?
Very good.
Hey, that's good then.
Have some watermelon.
Oh, the meat'll be here soon.
No rush.
Yeah.
What're you laughing at?
Mongke's just like this,
so warm you can't refuse him.
Hey, the meat's here!
Sorry for the wait.
Wow.
No worries, perfect timing.
You're the luckiest guest, y'know.
This mutton and pork buns
were all made fresh today.
Try some, try some.
Try some.
Yeah.
Know what this is?
What is it?
Ha ha ha.
This here's mare's milk wine.
Mare's milk wine?
Mare's milk wine's our grassland liquor.
Give it a taste, my friend.
Hey, this is good stuff.
Here.
Come come come come.
Let's all drink one together first.
Here.
Cheers.
Mm.
Hey, that's it.
Please, have some meat.
Here.
This is grassland custom.
Eating it shows respect.
Right, eat up, please eat.
Ha ha ha ha.
How is it?
Come come come come.
Please, have some more.
Mm.
Delicious.
Ha ha ha.
So good.
If it's good, drink some more.
Here, this bowl.
We're gonna welcome you
to our beautiful grasslands.
Welcome!
Always welcome.
Great.
Hey, my friend.
Hey, mm.
Mm.
Easy there,
don't get drunk and crash
at my place again.
Hey, at such a happy time,
Don't say such buzzkill stuff.
Hey, just this once.
I'm too happy today.
My good friend, Lei Zexin,
I'll remember that!
Lei Zexin.
This bowl,
let's just the two of us have a drink.
Cheers.
Uh...
your way of drinking...
Such big bowls all in one gulp?
Huh? What's wrong with that?
In... in bowls this big, where I'm from,
we sip bit by bit.
Ha ha.
Sip bit by bit?
Yeah.
Then how many sips for one bowl?
A bowl this big
about six to eight.
Ha ha ha ha ha.
Hey.
Then this whole jug,
you couldn't finish it even by dawn.
Ha ha ha ha ha.
Hey, listen,
since you've come to
our beautiful grasslands,
you gotta follow our grassland rules.
Fill it up, drink it down, okay?
Okay.
Yeah?
Yes, come come come, bottoms up.
Bottoms up.
Drink drink.
Hey! Ha ha ha ha.
I'll sing you a song.
My good friend.
Ha ha ha.
My good...
Good friend friend.
Good friend.
Hey.
Ha ha ha ha.
Go to sleep now, sleep.
Sleep.
Friend.
Friend, friend, friend.
Dance.
No more dancing, time to sleep.
Hey friend.
Mongke is really special.
He sure is.
With his snoring,
even wolves wouldn't dare come near.
I really envy you all.
Envy what?
I envy that you have the grasslands,
friends, and also the delicious...
Mare's milk wine.
Seriously though,
You've been away for so long.
Don't you miss seeing your parents?
My father passed away ten years ago.
My mother was so grief-stricken,
that seven years ago
she followed him.
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have asked.
It's alright.
It's been so long.
I've moved past it.
Then
why did you want to come to
the grasslands alone?
After going through so much,
I often feel that life in the city
has no meaning.
Especially lately.
I've been wanting to go somewhere by myself
to search for...
the meaning of life.
Have you found the meaning of life?
Lately I seem to have found something.
Hard to explain.
Can't quite put it into words.
Here's to those things
we can't quite explain.
I'm off.
Stay safe.
Take it slow.
Beautiful?
Beautiful.
What are you looking at?
I was talking about the scenery.
The scenery is beautiful too.
But you...
are even more beautiful.
Such a smooth talker.
I never knew why I came to the grasslands
and ended up here.
Today
I think I have an answer.
What?
These past few years,
I've often thought about a question.
If life
had only one day left,
how would I spend it?
You have an answer now?
Yes.
Just like
how I'm spending it right now.
Lei Zexin.
If you don't know where to go,
just stay here.
You've already sensed it, haven't you?
I've already sensed
that you're going to leave.
Lei Zexin.
As long as you don't leave,
we'll be together forever.
I really wish time could stop at this day.
That way,
we'd never have to be apart.
What the grasslands have most of is time.
I can take you to do so many things.
Go horseback riding,
herd sheep
and we can visit Mongke's farm.
There's so much to do.
How could one day be enough?
Amur.
There's something
I want to tell you.
Tell me.
Actually
I've met Xiaohei.
I knew it.
After all this time,
he's not coming back.
(Xiaohei)
Tell me, what happened to Xiaohei?
Amur.
I never intended to deceive you.
It's just...
I never knew how to tell you.
So
you mean it wasn't a wolf that bit you,
it was Xiaohei, wasn't it?
Amur, is that what you think?
What kind of misunderstanding happened
between you two?
Xiaohei wouldn't normally bite people.
This is what happened.
That day
I was hiking on the grasslands
planning to camp by the lake
but unexpectedly
I encountered a pack of wolves.
I tried to scare them off.
But the alpha caught me off guard
and charged at me, biting my hand.
Just when I had given up hope,
Xiaohei rushed out and saved me.
It was Xiaohei.
He fought with those wolves.
After that,
some herders arrived too.
But
I saw with my own eyes
as those wolves dragged Xiaohei away.
Only this dog tag was left behind.
So...
you didn't come here because you were lost.
Right.
I wasn't lost.
Then what was all of this? You coming here?
To compensate me?
Amur.
I did come because of Xiaohei
but now I truly love it here.
I could even take Xiaohei's place
and stay with you.
Let go.
You could never replace him.
Lei Zexin,
in this world,
no one can stay with anyone forever.
I can, I can stay with you forever.
If I die,
then bury me next to that meteorite.
To stay with you forever.
Just leave.
You've wanted to leave for a while now.
Now that you've said everything
you needed to.
You can leave with no regrets.
That's not what I meant.
Don't say any more, Lei Zexin.
Whether it was to repay a debt
or to atone,
you've done what you needed to do.
Now
it's time for you to leave.
Amur.
Mongke.
Here, perfect timing.
Have some morning tea.
Oh, thanks.
Hey, your invitation.
(Wedding Invitation)
She really can't stand being alone.
Do you want to go or not?
Hey, if you don't wanna go, just tell me.
I'll let Auntie Yalin know.
Mongke.
Who's getting married?
Hey, c'mon over, sit sit sit.
Sit sit sit.
Amur's mom.
And his fourth stepdad.
Oh, so he does have family.
Yeah.
See this guesthouse?
His mom left it to him.
But y'know
she hasn't been back for many years.
You should go now.
Hey.
I haven't even finished peeling this egg
and you're kicking me out?
I was talking to Lei Zexin.
After breakfast,
take the motorcycle out front and go.
Amur.
Why're you being like this?
Hey, Lei Zexin's your most important guest.
If he leaves, I'll be real sad, y'know.
Amur.
Mongke.
Is Amur really not going to
his mom's wedding?
Can you try to convince him?
Nah, no point.
He's just as stubborn as his mom.
Hey, remember to send me a message
when you arrive.
Don't make us worry.
Okay.
No problem, I will.
Amur.
I'm leaving.
This journey to the grasslands
has been complete.
All that's left is to consider
a final resting place.
Maybe back to Singapore.
Amur, go see your mom.
I've been praying to the Eternal Sky.
Hoping that somewhere in this world
there would be someone who
loves you more than I do.
I think that person
can only be her.
Amur.
Goodbye.
Now I finally believe
that meteorite traveling billions
of miles to reach this place.
It was always
its own choice.
Amur.
Are you alright?
I...
Son, don't be angry
with your mother anymore.
My son.
You've been through so much.
It's... it's Mom's fault.
Let Mom apologize to you, okay?
You don't have to.
Mongke said you're going to find someone
very important.
Somewhere very far away?
Singapore.
Alright, go find him.
If you have any difficulties...
Don't worry, Mom.
Passport and visa are all ready.
I have everything I need.
It's been so many years
since you called me Mom.
Son.
You've grown up.
Go find the person you're looking for.
No matter how far,
your mother supports you.
Mom.
I'm...
sorry I couldn't make it
to your wedding.
It's okay, it's okay, son,
Mom doesn't blame you.
Mom, don't cry.
It's nothing.
These are tears of happiness.
Amur.
Ha ha ha ha ha.
Oh man, you're finally gonna leave
the grasslands in your life!
As your friend,
I'm happy for ya.
Remember.
You gotta find Lei Zexin.
How did you know
I'd definitely go find Lei Zexin?
Ha ha ha.
Hey, between friends,
there ain't no secrets.
Mongke.
Mm?
I'll be back.
I know that, of course.
The person who can make you
leave the grasslands
will definitely bring you back too.
I'm going.
Go on.
Good luck.
(Xiaohei)
Hello?
Is this Mr. Amur?
Oh, yes it is.
Who is this?
My name is Du Bianyi.
I'm Lei Zexin's attending physician.
What happened to Lei Zexin?
He left the hospital a week ago.
He has no family members on record.
So in his file, he only listed
your name and phone number.
What's his condition?
He has Cerebral Vascular Malformation.
Commonly known as a brain aneurysm.
He really should have surgery immediately.
Of course, surgery has its risks
and the patient could have a brain
hemorrhage at any time.
So the operation is highly risky.
I first admitted Lei Zexin
a year and a half ago
but he only left a note in his room
saying "I want to spend the rest
of my life on natural time"
and then he disappeared.
Driver, driver!
Stop the car.
Recently he came back once.
We insisted he have surgery
but he left the hospital again.
So we're hoping to find him through you.
Standing here...
It's as if I'm standing
at the center of the world.
Amur.
Have you
ever felt that way?
If life...
had only one day left,
how would I spend it?
Just like
how I'm spending it right now.
Lei Zexin.
Amur.
You think,
maybe he never even came here?
With his body in such bad shape,
he might not have even made it here.
Ah, why'd I have to say that.
He will come back here.
I saw a marker over there.
Looks like it was set up for Xiaohei.
Look.
(Amur's guest)
It's him.
He came back.
He must be the one
who put this up for Xiaohei.
Hey Amur.
Amur, don't do that.
You'll hurt your hands, Amur.
He's right here.
Amur.
He must have come back..
It must be him.
Amur.
He's right here.
Stop it, Amur.
Oh, Amur.
He might not have come at all.
What are you doing? Why are you like this?
He wouldn't.
Xiaohei gave his life to save him.
He'll come back for me.
Amur.
I still want to spend the rest of my life
on natural time...
but, Amur,
I need to be with you.